So, how did the system know that the Maps
app could handle this Intent? The activity within the
Maps app included an intent filter like this one
within its manifest entry. It indicates that the Maps
app is capable of performing this view action on
all data which has a geo scheme. You can
use intent filters for your activities to define the
actions they're capable of performing, and optionally, the kind
of data that they can perform it on. So,
when you use an implicit intent to address or
request to start an activity, much like you did
with Catherine and the openweathermap.org link, Android resolves this request
by checking the intent filters of every activity that's
installed on the device until it finds the best possible
match. If multiple activities match, as in the case
with the web url, the user is given a choice.